Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
As the White Base fled Side 6...
...the Conscon Mobile Unit
continued its relentless attacks.
Thanks to the Gundam and other machines,
they were able to fight off the enemy.
However, the full-scale battle
has yet to begin.
The Glory of Solomon
Third Fleet approaching us
from the stern!
White Base, do you read me?
Loud and clear. Go ahead.
We're entering formation.
Hold your course.
We'll align in formation.
Prepare to receive supplies.
Tell him we acknowledge.
Yes, sir.
Columbus supply ship coming into our bow
from starboard.
Get them to load the supplies quickly.
I'll go pay a visit to the fleet commander.
How come I'm not allowed to go?
I wanna say hi to the commander!
This is no errand for children!
Don't let them treat you
like a child either, Lieutenant.
Lieutenant, help out with the supplies.
No fair!
There's some ugly-looking thing
carrying missiles, but what is it?
It's a Public-type assault ship.
Assault ship?!
Meaning we've got tough times ahead still.
Oh, I don't like this one bit.
Right. I'll leave it to you.
Captain.
The captain of the White Base has arrived.
Good. Thank you.
Lieutenant Junior Grade Bright Noa.
You've done well, Bright.
Good to see you again,
Commandant Wakkein.
"Commandant" isn't necessary.
When I'm with the top brass,
I'm quickly reduced to a minor officer.
Sir?
You're starting to look like a real commander.
Very admirable.
Look at this.
Sir!
This is the course we're presently on.
Our main forces are taking a wide detour.
But this is...!
So the target of the operation is Solomon?!
That's right.
The White Base will join us at
the vanguard in our attack on Solomon.
Is that so? That's a big responsibility.
Are we up to it?
The fact that you're able
to look at it that way...
...proves just how confident you've become.
You'll be fine.
But, sir. The White Base pilots
are all tremendously overworked.
Especially Amuro.
Oh, the Gundam boy.
He possesses an amazing talent.
He's different from us.
Different? How?
It's just a feeling.
The magnetic pressure won't increase.
That's a problem.
Your dinner's here.
Something the matter?
No. Just leave it there, please?
Thank you.
This isn't good...
There's only one Big Zam on the Papua?!
Yes, sir!
At present, that's all they...
What is my brother thinking?!
The Rick Doms we have won't be sufficient.
Why not send us 10 Doms
instead of one cutting-edge mobile suit?
Actually, sir...
Yes?!
This Big Zam is still in the prototype stage.
They're rushing development, but they
have so many requests from every front...
That's enough. Dismissed.
Yes, sir.
Assemble the Big Zam on the double!
Sir!
Haven't we located the Tianem Fleet yet?!
I'm afraid not, sir.
We're searching where the Minovsky particle
density is high, but with so many decoys...
What do you expect in a war?!
Hurry up with the supply loading!
Disengage conveyor pipes! Close off valves!
Check the internal air pressure at once!
Where's the harbor pilot?!
Thank you, Prosecutor Cameron.
Have you removed the weapon seals for us?
I've removed the seals,
but firing within Side 6 airspace is still...
I understand.
I hope you'll leave soon.
I don't want you to come here ever again.
Be careful with your words, Mr. Cameron.
Excuse me?
Side 6 has survived this long
because it's convenient for Zeon.
You'd do well to remember that.
Are you saying that we live by your whim?!
Lalah. What's taking you so long?
Who is that young lady...?
She's like a sister.
Let's leave it at that, shall we?
Our fleet is currently situated
at the third battle line...
...from the enemy space fortress, Solomon.
We're so close to them.
From here on, nothing stands between
the enemy and ourselves.
Here we go again.
Changing fleet formation to lateral line!
Fraw Bow!
Where are Katz, Letz, Kikka?
In E-Block of the gravitational core.
Haro, too?
Yes, sir.
Do we have to stay here and be quiet?
We can't fight unless we have these on!
We'll make a frontal attack.
Our Public assault ships
will create a beam interference field.
All vessels proceed directly ahead.
He's gotta be kidding. With a fleet this small,
this is practically suicide!
It'll be fine, Mr. Kai.
The Federation has things worked out.
That's easy for you to say, but...!
That's enough out of you, Kai.
We'll have to put our faith
in Tianem's main fleet.
You only need to hold out for 15 minutes.
In the meantime, the main fleet will use
its anti-fortress weapon.
Anti-fortress weapon?
What could it be?
Commence attack, minus 8!
All Publics, 3... 2... 1... 0!
Take off!
Well? What's up?
How far has the enemy closed in?
Sir! They're hiding in the debris of Side 4
as they continue to advance!
They're now within targeting range!
All right. Shoot them down!
Yes, sir!
Missiles! Main cannons! Beam cannons!
Prepare to fire!
Fire!
The enemy has created
a powerful beam interference field!
Rick Dom and Zaku forces,
prepare for enemy advance!
There aren't that many enemy vessels.
Switch to missile attack!
Milva Fleet, move to left wing!
Harvard Force, stay in the rear.
Tianem's main fleet will approach
from another direction!
The beam interference field is working!
Good! All vessels,
proceed at your own discretion!
Launch our GM and Ball mobile suit forces!
Mobile suits and G-Fighters,
begin launching!
Don't forget, this is a joint operation!
Don't fall behind, guys!
I only hope the Zanzibar's not here.
Sayla, launching!
Guncannon, taking off!
Here I go!
So, this is a battlefield.
Mobile Suit
Gundam
You bastard...!
Here's the first shot...
And next up...
Kai. Don't let your guard down.
Ms. Sayla! I love ya!
La Coque. Take over.
Yes, Admiral!
I'll be right back.
Sir!
Just in case, I want all women
moved to the escape capsules!
Hurry.
Is the battle going that badly?
Move it.
Yes, sir.
Our Solomon will never fall.
It's just a precaution.
Just in case something happens.
For Mineva, who has finally blessed us.
You spoke too loudly...!
Hurry now.
A little closer... Closer... That's the ticket.
Now!
Life or death?
No one knows the outcome
until the very end.
The only certainty is that
with every beautiful sparkle in the sky...
...people, or even hundreds of them...
...are becoming debris
littered through space.
Are the mirrors ready?
Sir! About 4 minutes longer.
Right. Solomon should detect us about now.
What?!
Fool! You just realized they're hiding
among the debris of Side 1?!
What's the matter?!
It's Tianem's main fleet!
Launch the satellite missiles!
What's that?!
Send the battleship Gwaran and
some Musais against their main fleet!
Should we ask the 7th Division for backup?
Thanks.
Help from Kycilia?
For such a minor skirmish...
We'd be the laughingstock of all Zeon.
Mirror deployment complete!
Attitude control vernier linkage system: OK!
Solar System target: Solomon's right flank!
The space gate!
10 seconds to axis alignment!
Interceptors approaching!
All ships, be alert!
Ignore them! Hurry with focus alignment!
3... 2... Focus is now on target!
S-Solomon!? It's burning up! So that's...
The power of the Federation's new weapon.
What's happening?!
Gate 6 has vanished!
The enemy's new weapon did this!
What is it?!
Nothing on radar!
No energy particle reactions!
Then it's some kind of laser?!
From where?!
The enemy's main fleet!
Isn't the Gwaran force headed there?
This is mega particle cannon 45.
Where should we be firing?
D-Dammit!
This is no good.
The cartridge lock is shot.
I'll have to retreat!
Guntank has returned with level B damage.
The pilot is injured.
With the Guntank's retreat,
fighting strength is down 11 percent.
Hayato's hurt?!
The number of injured people is increasing.
Please, let me go and help the medics!
Permission granted.
Baro, take over for Fraw.
Right away, sir.
Petty Officer Masaki!
Prepare for a transfusion!
You'll feel better soon.
Can I do anything to help?
Bring a unit of type AB blood
and a transfusion set.
Hayato!
Hurry!
Yes!
Enemy main fleet approaching!
Launch all the satellite missiles
in orbit right now!
You'll have to give Hayato another unit
of blood after this one. Don't forget it.
Okay.
Incoming! It's a Dom!
Fraw Bow?
Stay still.
You've fought more than enough already.
Now it's time for you to rest.
The others...?
They're all fine.
They're out there fighting.
Is that so?
It's so frustrating...
I'm the only one in this sorry state.
I can't even keep up
with Ms. Sayla and Mr. Kai...
I'm pathetic.
What are you saying, Hayato?!
You're doing a fine job too!
Don't try to comfort me, Fraw.
Ever since I joined the White Base crew
I've wanted nothing better...
...than to somehow beat Amuro.
But look at me!
Hayato.
Amuro's...
He's different...
He's different from us.
2nd and 6th Gattle combat squadrons,
no response! Gwaran, no response!
La Coque. Could you get me more coffee?
Yes!
Pull back all remaining mobile suits!
We'll wipe out the enemy
at Solomon's doorstep!
They're retreating?!
Where should I force my way in?!
So that's where the new weapon got them.
Incredible!
Here I go!
Message from the White Base.
It seems that one of our mobile suits
has entered Solomon!
Good! Instruct all ships
to launch their mobile suits!
Roger!
This is Titan calling all vessels!
Send out your GM and Ball
mobile suit assault teams!
Good luck, everybody!
Solomon's requesting reinforcements?
Yes.
The message is encrypted,
so we don't have any details...
...but Lady Kycilia's orders are
to head for Solomon.
Lalah. Are you ready?
You're finally headed for battle.
Zanzibar! Full speed ahead!
Destination, Solomon!
All hands to level 3 battle stations!
They finally left.
Thank goodness.
Mirai...
At the very least...
I hope you live a long life.
Is Zenna here?
Darling. Is something wrong?
Don't be silly! Solomon will never fall!
Then...?
I want you to escape
and go to my sister's Granada base.
Is it that hopeless?
It's going fine. Don't worry...
Take care of Mineva.
Make sure she grows up strong, Zenna.
Darling...!
I am a military man...
I'm a soldier who will uphold
the Zabi family tradition...
I won't die.
Go, Zenna! And take Mineva!
Assemble mobile suit forces on the double!
The enemy is about to land!
All remaining Rick Doms and Zakus!
Prepare for battle!
Gattle combat squadrons, launch
as soon as your missiles are reloaded!
Is the Big Zam ready for combat?
The final battle is yet to come!
So that's the Big Zam...
Vice Admiral Dozle's mobile armor
brushes aside the Federation Forces.
When Lieutenant Sleggar's desperate attack
breaks through the enemy's defense...
...Amuro witnesses...
...the shadow of hatred
that dwells within Dozle's heart.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Big Zam's Last Stand.
Will you be able to survive?
Next Time
Big Zam's Last Stand
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...